Guide to the Melville Cane Papers,
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Melville Cane Papers,
1901-1979.
Cane, Melville, 1879-1980.
22 linear ft (ca. 2,950 items in 46 boxes & 5 volumes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4079655
Biographical Note
American poet & lawyer whose career included important achievements in the fields of copyright law, book publishing, and the writing and publishing of poetry.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, and books of Melville H. Cane. Among the correspondents are Van Wyck Brooks, Carl Jung, Lewis Mumford, William Saroyan, Upton Sinclair, Felix Frankfurter, Jessamyn West, and W.H.Auden. Included is a scrapbook of newspaper articles by Cane, written chiefly for the "New York Evening Post". He served as the Columbia University correspondent during 1901 and 1902, when he was studying for his degree at the School of Law.
Arrangement
This collection is arranged into 8 series:
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Cataloged Manuscripts
Series III: Arranged Correspondence
Series IV: Books and Periodicals
Series V: Medals
Series VI: Manuscripts
Series VII: Subject Files
Series VIII: Oversize Material
Subjects
Auden, W. H. (Wystan Hugh), 1907-1973.; Bradley, William Aspenwall, 1878-1939.; Braithwaite, William Stanley, 1878-1962.; Brooks, Van Wyck, 1886-1963.; Cardozo, Benjamin N. (Benjamin Nathan), 1870-1938.; Cross, Wilbur L. (Wilbur Lucius), 1862-1948.; Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns), 1888-1965.; Erskine, John, 1879-1951.; Frost, Robert, 1874-1963.; Gregory, Alyse, 1884-1967.; Jung, C. G. (Carl Gustav), 1875-1961.; Lewis, Sinclair, 1885-1951.; Lincoln, Abraham, 1809-1865.; Maritain, Jacques, 1882-1973.; Moore, Marianne, 1887-1972.; Morley, Christopher, 1890-1957.; Mumford, Lewis, 1895-1990.; Munson, Gorham Bert, 1896-1969.; Nash, Ogden, 1902-1971.; O'Neill, Eugene, 1888-1953.; Orage, A. R. (Alfred Richard), 1873-1934.; Perkins, Maxwell E. (Maxwell Evarts), 1884-1947.; Rives, Amélie, 1863-1945.; Ross, Harold Wallace, 1892-1951.; Saroyan, William, 1908-1981.; Sinclair, Upton, 1878-1968.; Speyer, Leonora, 1872-1956.; Spingarn, Joel Elias, 1875-1939.; Stieglitz, Alfred, 1864-1946.; Thurber, James, 1894-1961.; Trilling, Lionel, 1905-1975.; West, Jessamyn.; Wheelock, John Hall, 1886-1978.; Wolfe, Thomas, 1900-1938.; Authors, American--20th century.; American literature--20th century.; American poetry.; English poetry.; Essays.; Lectures.; Manuscripts.; Poems.; Proofs.; Scrapbooks.; Lawyers.; Poets.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: 7-52. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
Acquisition
1968 M-19682 Cane. Melville Gift
Alternate Formats
W.H. Auden letters are on microfilm.
Gift of Melville Cane, 1968, 1972, 1974, 1976, & 1978; of Mrs Helen Kaufmann, 1977; of Paul Gitlin, 1985.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  Cataloged Correspondence and Manuscripts are Interfiled
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce To Melville H. Cane, New York, [Sept 1929], (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce To Melville H. Cane, New York, [13 Dec 1935], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce To Melville H. Cane, New York, 24 May 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Franklin Pierce To Melville H. Cane, New York, 3 July 1942, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Adams, Leonie To Melville H. Cane, New York, 25 May 1925, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh To Melville H. Cane, Swarthmore, PA, 13 April 1945, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Auden, Wystan Hugh To Melville H. Cane, Swarthmore, PA, 14 April [1946], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Auslander, Joseph To Melville H. Cane, New York, 16 Jan 1934, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Benet, Laura To Melville H. Cane, New York, 31 May 1973, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Benet, Laura To Melville H. Cane, [New York], 6 June 1973, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose To Melville H. Cane, New York, 15 Feb 1934, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [With copy of reply]
  - Benet, William Rose To Melville H. Cane, New York, 17 Feb 1934, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose To Melville H. Cane, New York, 2 March 1935, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Benet, William Rose To Melville H. Cane, New York, 30 Jan 1948, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall To Melville H. Cane, New York & Paris, 1901-1929, (11 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall To Melville H. Cane, Paris, 14 March 1926, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Bradley, William Aspenwall To Melville H. Cane, Paris, 1930-1939, (16 a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley To Melville H. Cane, Arlington Heights, MA, 6 April 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Braithwaite, William Stanley To Melville H. Cane, Arlington Heights, MA, 25 July 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville H. Cane, Westport, CT, 24 Dec 1923, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville H. Cane, Westport, CT, 1 Dec 1931, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville H. Cane, Westport, CT, 28 Dec 1931, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville H. Cane, Westport, CT, 16 Oct 1938, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville H. Cane, Westport, CT, 20 Oct 1938, (1 p.c.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Alfred Harcourt, Westport, CT, 20 Oct 1938, (1 p.c.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Florence Cane, Westport, CT, 27 Oct 1938, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Florence Cane, Westport, CT, 29 March 1939, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 4 April 1939, (1 page a.l.s. (s. with initials)) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 22 May 1939, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 30 May 1939, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 30 Nov 1941, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 4 Nov 1943, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, 20 Sept 1946, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Westport, CT, Dec 1955, (1 page Christmas card) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, Bridgewater, CT, 9 March 1957, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Brooks, Van Wyck To Melville Cane, West Tisbury, MA, 13 June 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Burke, Kenneth To Melville Cane, New York, 17 Sept 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville To Joel Spingarn, New York, 25 April 1905, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville To Abraham Valentine Williams Jackson, New York, [17 Oct 1930], (1 page a.l.s. (top half of letter cut off)) (Box 1)
    [Enclosure: "Two Stars", a.ms.s., 1 page (poem; copy)]
  - [Cane, Melville] To The New Yorker, [New York], 19 Dec 1939, (1 page t.l. (carbon)) (Box 1)
    [For the above See: Ross, Harold W. To Melville Cane, 27 Dec 1939.]
  - Cane, Melville To Sinclair Lewis, New York, 28 Dec 1943, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
    [For the above See: Lewis, Sinclair. To [Melville Cane], 29 Dec [1943].]
  - [Cane, Melville] To Mrs. Eugene O'Neill, [New York], 3 June 1948, (2 pages t.l. (carbon)) (Box 1)
    [For the above See: O'Neill, Eugene. To Melville Cane, 6 June 1948.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1957-1959 & n.d., (11 a.l.s., 2 a.n.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 5 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1960-1961, (4 a.l.s., 2 t.l.s., 3 a.p.c.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 11 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1962-1963, (10 a.l.s., 2 a.p.c.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1964-1965, (7 a.l.s., 1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 10 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, New York & Denver, 1966, (5 a.l.s., 3 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 3 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1967, (5 a.l.s., 4 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, New York & Denver, 1968-1969, (3 a.l.s., 3 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 6 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1970-1971, (4 a.l.s., 7 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 4 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, New York & Denver, 1972, (4 a.l.s., 4 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
    [With 2 related items.]
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, Denver, 1973-1974, (8 a.l.s., 3 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cane, Melville To Helen L. Kaufman, v.p., 1975-1977, (8 a.l.s., 7 a.p.c.s., 1 a.n.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 4 Nov 1925, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - [Cardozo, Benjamin N.] To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Jan 1928, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 2 Oct 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, [1928], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 27 May 1928, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Dec 1929, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Albany, 27 March 1930, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Albany, 13 June 1930, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 3 July 1930, (1 page t.l.s. (s. with initials)) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 18 Dec 1931, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Dec 1931, (1 page a.l.s. (s. with initials)) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 20 Jan 1932, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 24 Feb 1932, (1 page t.l.s., 1 a.n. (on the same page)) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, New York, 4 March 1932, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Rye, NY, 24 June 1933, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Washington, 29 Dec 1934, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Washington, 30 Dec 1934, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Washington, 6 Jan 1935, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Washington, 8 Jan 1935, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Rye, NY, 18 July 1935, (3 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cardozo, Benjamin N. To Melville Cane, Washington, 15 March 1936, (2 pages ms.l.s. (written and s. by Joseph Rank, Jr., for Justice Cardozo)) (Box 1)
  - Ciardi, John To Melville Cane, New York, [1956?], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ciardi, John To Melville Cane, New York, 20 March 1956, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Ciardi, John To Melville Cane, New York, 25 Feb 1959, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Colum, Padraic To Melville Cane, New York, 1 June 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Colum, Padraic To Melville Cane, New York, 13 June 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Colum, Padraic To Melville Cane, Woods Hole, MA, 20 July 1947, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Colum, Padraic To Melville Cane, Woods Hole, MA, 12 Sept 1966, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman To Melville Cane, New York, 11 Sept 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman To Melville Cane, New York, 19 July 1948, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cousins, Norman To Melville Cane, Lambertville, NJ, 7 May 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cross, Wilbur To Melville Cane, New Haven, CT, 1925-1928, (8 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Cross, Wilbur To Melville Cane, New Haven, CT, 1929-1939, (12 t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette To Melville Cane, New York, 10 April 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Deutsch, Babette To Melville Cane, New York, 12 April 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - DeVries, Peter To Melville Cane, Chicago, 8 Nov 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Eberhart, Richard To Melville Cane, Washington, 18 Jan 1960, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Eberhart, Richard To Melville Cane, Washington, 26 Jan 1960, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Eberhart, Richard To Melville Cane, Washington, 26 Feb 1960, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Edman, Irwin To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 18 May 1944, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 29 May 1947, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - [Eliot, Thomas Stearns] To Melville Cane, Princeton, NJ, 9 Nov 1948, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 1)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns To Melville Cane, London, 1 March 1956, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Eliot, Thomas Stearns To Melville Cane, London, 7 Nov 1955, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Jan 1926, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Sept 1929, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 2 Jan 1934, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 3 June 1938, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Florence Cane, New York, 5 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 15 April 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 16 May 1939, (3 pages t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Erskine, John To Melville Cane, New York, 8 April 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 1)
  - Flagler, Harry Harkness To Melville Cane, Millbrook and New York City, NY, 1919-1943, (3 a.l.s., 1 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Flagler, Harry Harkness To Melville Cane, Millbrook, NY, 7 July 1933, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With 2 related letters]
  - Frankfurter, Felix To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 1 July 1932, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Frankfurter, Felix To Melville Cane, Washington, 28 May 1947, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Frankfurter, Felix To Melville Cane, Washington, June 1947, (1 page a.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Frost, Robert To Melville Cane, Amherst, MA, 18 Nov 1937, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Frost, Robert To Melville Cane, Gainsville, FL, 23 Dec 1937, (1 Christmas card (with envelope)) (Box 2)
  - Frost, Robert To Melville Cane, [Cambridge, MA], 26 June 1960, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Gilder, Jeannette L. To Melville Cane, New York, 8 Jan 1907, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Ginsberg, Louis To Melville Cane, Paterson, NJ, 21 May 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Giroux, Robert To Melville Cane, New York, 21 Feb 1952, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Greenslet, Ferris To Melville Cane, Boston, 17 May 1904, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Greenslet, Ferris To Melville Cane, Boston, 14 Jan 1944, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Gregory, Alyse To Melville Cane, New York, 8 Sept 1924, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Gregory, Alyse To Melville Cane, New York, 26 Jan 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Gregory, Alyse To Melville Cane, New York, 28 March 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hand, Learned To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Feb 1940, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hand, Learned To Melville Cane, Windsor, VT, 17 July 1953, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Harcourt, Alfred To Melville Cane, New York, 1 Aug 1919, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, n.d., (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, [New York], n.d., (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 15 Nov 1968, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 22 Nov 1968, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, Philadelphia, 28 Feb 1969, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 9 July 1969, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 2)
    [With related item]
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 18 June 1971, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 25 Aug 1971, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 31 Aug 1971, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, Washington, 2 Feb 1972, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 19 Feb 1972, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, Washington, 29 Feb 1972, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 6 March 1972, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, New York, 13 Aug 1972, (6 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Haydn, Hiram To Melville Cane, Washington, 11 Oct 1973, (1 page t.l.s. (s. by sec'y)) (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert To Melville Cane, Delaware, 3 Dec 1952, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert To Melville Cane, Delaware, 15 March 1956, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert To Melville Cane, Delaware, 1 Feb 1958, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hillyer, Robert To Melville Cane, Delaware, 1 July 1958, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Hubbard, Elbert To Melville Cane, East Aurora, NY, 25 Jan 1899, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Huebsch, Benjamin To Melville Cane, New York, 16 Nov 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Huebsch, Benjamin To Melville Cane, New York, 6 Dec 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Huebsch, Benjamin To Melville Cane, New York, 26 March 1951, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood To Melville Cane, New York, 29 July 1901, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Johnson, Robert Underwood To Melville Cane, New York, 20 June 1904, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, n.p., 19 March 1964, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With 4 related items]
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 19 June 1970, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 3 Jan 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 15 April 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With envelope and related telegram]
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 12 Aug 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Oct 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 22 Nov 1974, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Melville Cane, New York, 17 March 1975, (4 pages t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jovanovich, William To Staff [of Harcourt, Brace, Jovanovich], [New York], 13 May 1975, (1 page t.l.s. (memorandum; photocopy)) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav To [Melville Cane], Kussnacht-Zurich, 14 June 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav To Melville Cane, Zurich, 5 Sept 1932, (1 page p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav To Melville Cane, Kusnacht-Zurich, 8 May 1953 - 16 March 1956, (2 t.l.s. (s. by sec'ies)) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav To, n.p., 29 July 1926, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Gustav To Peter [H.G. Baynes], Sills-Maria, Switzerland, 12 Aug 1926, (1 page a.l.s. (introducing Melville Cane)) (Box 2)
  - Jung, Carl Mrs. To Melville Cane, Zurich, 12 Dec 1933, (4 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 6 Oct 1928, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 4 Nov 1929, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Kirstein, Lincoln To Melville Cane, Cambridge, MA, 13 Nov 1929, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Kreymborg, Alfred To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Aug 1953, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To [Melville Cane], [New York?], [1926], (1 page t.l.s. (incomplete - end of letter only, with s.)) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To [Melville Cane], n.p., 20 Feb 1926, (1 a.n.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To Melville Cane, London, 15 Feb 1933, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To Melville Cane, New York, 17 Dec 1937, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To Melville Cane, New York, 22 May 1939, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To [Melville Cane], Williamstown, MA, 8 June 1946, (1 a.n.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To Melville Cane, Williamstown, MA, 29 April 1947, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Lewis, Sinclair To Melville Cane, Williamstown, MA, 6 June [1948], (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Loveman, Amy To Melville Cane, New York, 1930-1939, (10 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With copies of 3 related letters]
  - Loveman, Amy To Melville Cane, New York, 1940-1944, (9 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With copy of related letter]
  - Loveman, Amy To Melville Cane, New York, 1945-1951, (11 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
    [With copies of 2 related letters]
  - Loveman, Amy To Melville Cane, New York, 1952-1955, (10 t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - McCord, David To Melville Cane, [Woodstock, VT], [22 Aug 1944], (1 p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Maritain, Jacques To Melville Cane, Princeton, NJ, 20 Feb 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Maritain, Jacques To Melville Cane, Princeton, NJ, 14 March 1954, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Maritain, Jacques To Melville Cane, Princeton, NJ, 12 Nov 1954, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Maritain, Jacques To Melville Cane, Princeton, NJ, 2 April 1956, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To Melville Cane, Chicago, 18 June 1926, (2 pages a.c.) (Box 2)
  - Monroe, Harriet To Melville Cane, Chicago, 21 May 1934, (1 page a.c.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 5 June 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 10 June 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 13 Aug 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 19 Aug 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 22 Aug 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Dec 1925, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 8 Feb 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 25 March 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 7 June 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 30 July 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 7 Sept 1926, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 20 Jan 1927, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 27 Oct 1927, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 9 April 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 30 Aug 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 25 Oct 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 12 Nov 1928, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, 7 Nov 1948, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Moore, Marianne To Melville Cane, New York, [3 March 1967], (1 t.p.c.s.; ms.n.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, New York, 16 June 1944, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 22 June 1945, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 5 Feb 1949, (1 t.p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, London, 17 Oct 1949, (1 a.p.c.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 16 Dec 1949, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 4 July 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 4 Sept 1950, (1 page a.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 30 Oct 1950, (1 page t.l.s.) (Box 2)
  - Morley, Christopher To Melville Cane, Roslyn Heights, NY, 24 Feb 1951, (1 p.c.) (Box 2)
  - Mumford, Lewis To Melville Cane, Amenia, NY, 24 Dec 1938, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Mumford, Lewis To Melville Cane, Amenia, NY, 3 Jan 1939, (2 pages t.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Mumford, Lewis To Melville Cane, New York, 28 Sept 1939, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 3)
  - Mumford, Lewis To Melville Cane, Amenia, NY, 17 July 1940, (2 pages a.l.s.) (Box 3)